Do you feel like there's space for a
context engineer role
>> [music]
>> or a memory engineer role? I would say
yes, but would they be called memory
engineers or context engineers? It's
something we're yet to see, but memory
engineering is nothing new. Memory
engineering is just a cross-section
between a couple of disciplines, which
includes database engineers, search
optimization engineers, software [music]
engineers, and a bit of AI engineering.
If you just cross-pollinate, you're
going to go into memory engineering,
which is a set of engineers that really
focus on optimizing the retrieval
pipelines within an agentic system.
>> And would you say memory [music]
management is a superset of context
management generally?
>> Yeah, it's an interesting debate.
I see everything
as memory. Memory actually is a good way
to bridge the gap between people's
knowledge of non-technical and
technical. So, when I say memory to my
mom or my grandmom, they understand what
I'm talking about. But, if I said
context,
They don't have the context of it.
>> Yeah, they don't have the context of it.
>> But, um memory really brings people into
that same understanding
um landscape, where you can start to
build upon it. So, when I say, "Hey,
we have agents in our phone, and they
need to remember." So, every information
you give into an agent, the agent is
that's actually memory.
>> Yeah. So, it starts to allow you to
think about ways you can improve the
the chances of that specific information
being recalled.
>> Yeah. You start to about ways you can
optimize your retrieval pipelines. So,
this is where we're heading towards, and
that's how I That's why I see everything
as memory, but you can argue
maybe everything is context.
>> Mhm. I'd love to kind of like hear your
thoughts in terms of, okay, skills.
Where Where do they sit in in relation
to context? And And even at Tesla, we
have that question like, "When we put
stuff on the website, should we Should
we say skills and then context?" Well,
you know, the the the kind of part
overlaps as well. Where Where do skills
sit in?
It's very important to get the naming
right within this phase of it.
>> Harder than naming it, though. It's very
hard to say. And cuz it moves so
quickly, you're like, "Okay, we can't
use that anymore."
>> This month we'll say skills.
>> We'll say skills. Next month [laughter]
we'll say something else. And no one was
saying skills last year, like early last
year, right? So, but where do we see
skills in this whole thing?
Again, I'm a very simple man. Let me go
back to humans.
Um skills are nothing new. Humans have
the equivalent, and they're called SOPs.
Standard operating procedures, which are
documentation that you have within
organizations that define how you do
certain tasks. And the reason why we had
SOPs is because you might have a certain
way of doing things, and let's say you
hire someone else, and you want to be
able to transfer that knowledge to
someone. The best way we saw as humans
to do that was to document it. And
really document in a structured way,
where you define the steps by step pro
step-by-step process you have to take to
achieve a certain outcome. And we call
that we call
They're called SOPs.
>> Yeah. And we have them in organizations
today. Skills are SOPs for agents,
right? It's just a way of telling an
agent
there is a task, and I'm going to give
an arbitrary name to the task, then I'm
going to describe the task in in in a
certain length, then I'm going to give
you step-by-step instructions and maybe
the locations of tools and scripts or
MCPs that allows you to achieve this um
the outcome of the that we want from
this task execution. And that's what
skills are. So, where do they fall into
the domain? Well, if you come into the
world of agent memory, you're going to
realize that skills are actually a form
of procedural memory, right? Humans have
procedural memory in our brain. There is
a part of our brain responsible for
storing and understanding skills that we
have. For example, if you can do a
backflip,
awesome if you can do a backflip. I
don't know if you can do a
>> backflip, Simon. I wish I Not Not at my
age, come on. Come on.
>> [laughter]
>> I I put I put
I put my back out getting my dog on the
lead these days. I don't know if I can
do a backflip.
>> [laughter]
>> I don't know. I've seen some old people
do backflips these days.
Um but, if you can do a backflip, where
that knowledge actually stored is
something called a cerebellum in your
brain, and that stores a bunch of
procedural knowledge that you have, the
ways you do routines and tasks.
Skills, and if you look at things from
the agent memory memory perspective,
skills are procedural knowledge for your
agent.